Guide to the ARS Audiotape Collection ARS.0070
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 35. K. Hart Smith Trust donation, 1962; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
  Tape 2. Side A: KCBS news broadcast of news conference featuring an interview by Bob Elliott and Ray Goulding with John P. Parsons, Executive Vice President of Trans-Hill, newest owners of the Mark Hopkins Hotel after it was sold by George D. Smith the previous week. The discussion is on the future of the Mark Hopkins Hotel. Side B: [KCBS] radio broadcast. Bill Weaver interviews actor Brad Dillman [i.e. Bradford Dillman] about his latest film, "St. Francis of Assisi," and his film career. Followed by Bill Weaver interview with Arthur Fiedler on the occasion of Summer Pops in San Francisco.
  7.5 ips, 4-track, mono, acetate, recorded both sides. Head out. Preservation wound 4/17/2012.
- 36. Norman H. Strouse donation 1983
  From donor's list: Dubbing: Welcome Mr. Strouse (5"); Dubbings: Misc. Music, Speeches By Mr. Strouse. See also instantaneous disc collection.
  - "Is Thompson On An Art Kick?" Ladies' Luncheon, 1967-10-27; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - Grolier Club, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - Address, Kansas City Chapter of Association of Industrial Advertisers, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - General Pershing from the Battlefields of France; Ambassador James W. Gerard. Dub from Columbia Gramophone Nation's Forum disc c.1918, 1 audiotape reel(s) 4" reel (Box 11)
  - Welcome Mr. Strouse, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
- 37. Syncom, 1963-1964
  - Voice of America: Kennedy and Balewa (Nigerian Prime Minister), First Communication Via Satellite. English Syncom, 1963-08-23; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
  - Story Line program with Ruth Ashton, CBS Guests Paul Norsell, HAC and Alton Jones, GSFC. Demonstration of Telephone Calls via Syncom II, 1964-04-01; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
- 38. Arnold and Joanna Tish donation 1990
  - Farewell To Ike, Tribute to Eisenhower, NBC News KRON, 1961-01-10; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969
  - Ogden Nash at Foothill College, 1962-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    Nash, Ogden
  - Wall Street Speaks to Chet Huntley (dub from LP set?), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
  - Robert Frost University of California Men’s Gymnasium. dub made 1963, 1953; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    Frost, Robert
  - Tribute to Herbert Hoover on evening of his death. NBC, KNBR Radio. recorded off–air, last half of 60 min. program, 1964-10-20; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964
  - SF Symphony. Mozart. Overture to Don Giovanni; Mozart. B flat Major piano concerto, Rudolph Ferkaney [i.e. Rudolf Firkusny?], piano; Interview with violist; Kripps conducting on eve of his 65th birthday. KKHI broadcast, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    Removed from Stanford misc.
- 39. Voice of Firestone
  Stevens, Risë; Speaks, Margaret; Voice of Firestone (Radio program); Steber, Eleanor; Crooks, Richard; Swarthout, Gladys
  - Voice of Firestone, tape 1. If I could tell you / Richard Crooks -- In my garden; If I could tell you / Eleanor Steber, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  - Voice of Firestone, tape 2. Bluebirds / Barlow -- Do you recall / Schumsky -- You are the song in my heart / Eleanor Steber -- In my garden / Eleanor Steber -- If I could tell you / Lynch, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  - Voice of Firestone, tape 3. Melody of love / Mack Morgan and the Cities Service Chorus – You’ re the song in my heart / Gladys Swarthout -- Melody of love / Richard Crooks, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  - Voice of Firestone, tape 4. If I could tell you / Richard Crooks -- In my garden / Richard Crooks -- Love is a song in my heart / Margaret Speaks, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  - Voice of Firestone, tape 5. Rise Stevens, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
  - Voice of Firestone, tape 6. Idabelle Firestone Memorial Program. Rise Stevens with Howard Barlow's Chorus and Orchestra, 1954-07-12; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
- 40. Miscellaneous items
  Single tapes with little or no known provenance, many of which are copies.
  - 3-5" reels
    - Putnam Aldrich encores, Berkeley recital, 1962; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Robert Ernest Babcock statement related to arrest, 1959-06-29; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Jean Berger. Vision of Peace. Olaf C. Christiansen, St. Olaf Choir. Dubbed from St. Olaf Records DLP 6. Received 1977, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Tristam Cary. Nonet (Computer Music), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
      Cary, Tristam
    - Chen Yu-Hsin (1912-1968) “Lullaby,” with recordings of several other Chinese composers, 1 audiotape reel(s) and music manuscript (Box 3)
    - Elgar. Pomp & Circumstance No. 1, 4 Trios only. “For School of Education”, 1971-1974; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - King George V 25th Jubilee Address, CBS overseas broadcast (transfer from aluminum disc), 1935-03-06; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      George V, King of Great Britain
    - Grapelli/Liang/Reinhardt, Paris, mid-‘30s, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Adolf Hitler pre-war speeches (Peteler Documentation, Germany, 1970), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - Dan Lewis Plastic Containers [sound effects, interview snippets, etc.], 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Lawrence Olivier's scenes from Shakespeare's Henry V and Hamlet; Muir Mathieson, Philharmonia Orchestra, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - R.M. Schafer, Prayer Book of Tibetan Dead, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    - Alexander Siloti, 193-? (transferred from cassette 1987), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
      Siloti, Alexander, 1863-1945
    - Voice of Vietnam; [Lt. Commander Richard A.] Stratton Confesses, 1967-03-04; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      Stratton, Richard A.
    - Anson Weeks, Wally King. 50th anniversary broadcast on KSFO, 1967-05; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    - Stuff of the Cosmos, Radio UNESCO program #7180 (14:20), 1960-03-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 18)
    - Celtic Tradition of Song, Radio UNESCO program #7309 (14:30), 1960-03-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 18)
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian,Partitas, harpsichord, BWV 830, E minor. Ray McIntyre, harpsichord., undated; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 18)
      McIntyre, Ray
  - 7" reels
    - American Airlines #21, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Mixed Up, by John and Jerry Arthur, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Bach, etc. flute and harpsichord music (German BASF tape), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Conversation With Ernst Bacon by Frederick Berndt, Orinda, Calif., 1986-02-27; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
      Transferred from Berndt cassette original 5/1986
      Bacon, Ernst
    - John Barrymore, Cornelia Skinner, John Gielgud, Gertrude Stein, e.e. cummings, George Rylands. Dubs from discs, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Robert L. Bauernschmidt. Schoenberg Trio; Berg String Qt. Opus 3, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - BBC recordings: Trinnimus by Plautus; The Way of The World excerpts (BBC World Theatre); Geoffrey Keynes- Henry James in Cambridge, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    - Lazar Berman, National Symphony Orchestra, Dorati. Tchaikovsky, op. 23; Copland, Lincoln Portrait; Marian Anderson; Daphnis and Chloe. U.N. Day. Dubbed from transcriptions, 1976-10-24; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Bull Dog Drummond (radio play)– two programs, dubbed from discs, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Cylinder Dubs-- Deakins (mostly Edison Blue Amberols), 5 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Cylinder Dubs-- Mapleson, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Dead Souls And Other Russian Readings (disc transfers, including Monitor MR-103, Dead Souls from eight sides on orig. USSR recordings), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    - Debussy recital, Marguerite Long, piano, 1982; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
      Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918
    - Debussy. Preludes, Book II. Artis Wodehouse, piano (with program), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
    - Delibes. Lakmé. Pelletier, Metropolitan Opera, 1940-01-06; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 9)
    - Karen Fantus, soprano, Becca Raffaelli, piano. Senior recital, Boston University, 1974-05; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Kirsten Flagstad Potpouri. copy of original tape, 1953-1956; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
      Flagstad, Kirsten
    - Speeches by Francisco Franco; Speeches by other Italian leaders, 1915-1919. dubs from RCA, Odeon LPs, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - Erich Fromm speaking on the subject of mental illness, interviewed by Huston Smith on Search for America, KQED (recorded off television with mic), 1960-01-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
      Fromm, Erich
    - Germann Naumovich Andreev speech, 1984-07-25; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    - Giovinezza, Inno Dei Facisti (Fascist marching anthem); Giovanni Martinelli, tenor (transfers from Victor discs?), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Hebrew Music (for holidays- from commercial recordings), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Hollywood Bowl; Standard Hour; Detroit Symphony. Donated by Victor Ledin, 1975, 1946-1952; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Historic Voices and Music from World War II; Hitler’s Inferno Vol.2 (both transfers from commercial releases) OR-200 in ARS, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    - George Houle - Examples from Engramelle. Executed at CCRMA, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
      digitized
      ARS0070_b15_01_pm.wav
    - Dorothy Kirsten on Your Hit Parade. Probable dub from disc, 1949; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      Kirsten, Dorothy
    - Om Kulsum - Egyptian Singer of an old age. Turkish, 1968-05-17; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    - Leary, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Libertarianism C.U. 20 October, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - The Speech of Colonel Charles A. Lindbergh - delivered in the Arena in St. Louis, 1941-05-10; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    - Ed Linotti and others: “It Just Happened” audio art; Drums of the Yoruba, 1969; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
      Ed Linotti, A Palo Alto record collector and nostalgia buff, was archivist at the Archive of Recorded Sound in the early 1970's. Linotti passed away in 1988 at the age of 46.
    - Makropolos Case 3.75 Dolby, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Diane Middlebrook, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
      Middlebrook, Diane Wood
    - Milhaud. La Tragedie Humaine. Milhaud, San Diego Symphonic Chorale. dub made 1967, 1960-12-20; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. La tragédie humaine, op.369
    - Accademia Monteverdiana, Monteverdi Quatercentenary Program. Conductor - Denis Stevens, Reel 1&2, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    - Moon Flight, TV News on Location, First Man on the Moon, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Mt. Zion Social Work Play, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Malcolm Muggeridge Interview, 1962-12-24; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
      Muggeridge, Malcolm
    - French Music Makers #13: The Musique Concrete, French Broadcast System [KZSU reel], 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - Nightbeat 1950-07-03; Tales of the Texas Rangers 1951-03-11 [radio programs], 1950-1951; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Offenbach. Tales of Hoffman. Conducted by Antonio de Almeida, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
      Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Contes d'Hoffmann
    - Palestrina, Motets. Theobald Schrems, Regensberg Cathedral Choir, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      Palestrina, Giovanni Pierluigi da, 1525?-1594. Motets
    - Cortland Palmer, Nilly, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Piatigorsky and Pavlovsky; Kozcalski; Niemczyk and Sulikowski recitals, transferred from cassettes 1986, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Ezra Pound, Le Testament de Francois Villon, BBC performance, 1962-07; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      Copy of copy of original from Hugh Kenner with no public performance or FM broadcasting provision.
      Pound, Ezra
    - Psalm 24, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Radio Nacional de Espana, Spanish Renaissance composers. Transferred from soundtrack to film from 1950. Juan de la Encina, Francisco Soto de Langa, Cristobal Morales, Tomas Luis de Victoria, Juan Batista Gomez, Rey Alfonso el Sabio, etc., 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - Leonard Ratner, Peer Gynt tape, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Reels numbered 125-160, primarily opera. #141-142, 174 labeled “Interviews, Misc., Trivia”, 36 audiotape reel(s) (Box 5)
    - Reels numbered 161-177, opera and unidentified, 17 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    - Loren Rush. The Cloud Messenger. Ozawa, Boston Symphony Orchestra; Kelterborn, Changements. San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, 1975-02-26; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      Rush, Loren, 1935- Cloud messenger; Kelterborn, Rudolf, 1931- Changements
    - R.W.: Baller; Full Sound; Baller and Resto test recording in Living Room, 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Kaija Saariaho. Sah Den Vogeln; Laconisme De L’aile; Imtraute, 1980-1982; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
      Saariaho, Kaija
    - Mort Sahl commentary; William O. Douglas address, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Saint-Saens. Piano Concerto No.5 in F Major, Op. 103. Ozawa, San Francisco Symphony, Jeanne-Marie Darre (recorded from KKHI), 1969-01-31; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
    - Salzburg Festival, Austria. Program No.14, 1959; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 15)
    - Sartre. Nekrassov. With Maurice Denham, Richard Goolden, Valerie White, Anthony Jacobs, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
      Sartre, Jean-Paul
    - Schumann. Scenes from Faust. Leinsdorf, Boston Symphony Orchestra, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
      Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Scenen aus Göthe's Faust
    - Shostakovitch. Symphony No.5 in D Major Opus 47. Stokowski, Stadium Symphony Orchestra, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
      Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 47, D minor
    - Sibelius. Concerto for Violin and Orchestra, op.47. Stokowski, Philadelphia Orchestra, Heifetz, 1934-12-24 (Box 12)
    - Sing-a-long TV Floradora Sextette [dub from Waggener disc?], 1964-01-06; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Singers, reels 1-6. Patti, Melba, Caruso, Tamagno, Lehmann, Sembrich, Joachim, Sarasate, Garden and Sembruch, 6 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - Bill Smith Trio Live at the Merchant’s Café Seattle, 1973-06-29; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
      Bill Smith, clarinet; Tom Collier, percussion; Dan Dean, guitar
    - Leland Smith. Concert for Orchestra, WNYC. Mt7-25, 1961; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
      Smith, Leland, 1925-
    - Songs of the Soviet Civil War; Dalmatian folk songs “dub of unidentified record", 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Speeches from 1920 presidential campaign; William Jennings Bryant excerpt from 1908 lecture, "Immortality" 1920. dubs from discs on Columbia National Forum series and Victor, 1908-1920; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - Dr. Margaret Steger Hypnoidal Session, 1955-09-06; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Pamela R. Stephens, organ recital at St. Marks, Berkeley. Buxtehude, Mendelssohn, Bach, 1973-12-09; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - “STP” in light pencil on boxes: 1. Rigoletto; Verdi Requiem; Beethoven Symphony IX -- 2. Macbeth; Hugenotti; Boris Hi-Lites -- 3. [Scheherazade?]; [Andrea C?], 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - Tchaikovsky. 1812 Overture, Hamburg Symphony Orchestra, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. 1812 année
    - Dylan Thomas Reading at UCLA, dubs from UCLA, 1950-04-10; 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
      Thomas, Dylan
    - Virgil Thomson. Symphony No.2, Ozawa, San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, 1975-12-03; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
      dub of master at Yale University, donated by Sandor Salgo
      Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989. Symphonies, no. 2, C major
    - Virgil Thomson. Symphony No.2, Mitropoulos, from U.T., 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - Toscanini. Danza Delle Ondine Rehearsal, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
      transferred 1982 from Fagan Collection 12” lacquer B-51
      Catalani, Alfredo, 1854-1893. Loreley. Danza delle ondine
    - Peter Ustinov, German musicologist routine; Rev. Abernathy, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 7)
    - H.G. Wells, War of the Worlds, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Orson Welles, War of the Worlds "used by Hadley Cantril in writing his book…" gift of Prof. John W. Dodds 1975, 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 10)
    - Welsh church service and sing, "gymanfa ganu", 1965; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - Jesse Colin Young live broadcast KSAN from Boarding House, San Francisco 1973-09-18 (possibly also Boz Scaggs KSAN live broadcast from Paramount Theatre, Oakland 1974-03-10, marked on box but not marked on reel), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 11)
    - AMPEX Demonstration Tape AT-17, 1 audiotape reel(s) folders (Box 18)
    - Chafe, Chris. Marienbad. Alea II concert in Dinkelspiel Auditorium, 1980-05-27 (Box 18)
      Chafe, Chris. Marienbad. Anne Witherell, trombone; Peter Pesic, violin; Andrew Schloss, vibraphone; Jonathan Berger, tape operator. Recorded in an Alea II concert in Dinkelspiel Auditorium, May 27, 1980.
      Chafe, Chris
    - Schubert: Sonata, B flat major; Brahms: Intermezzo; Bach: Partita; Ray McIntyre, piano (Box 18)
      Schubert, Franz, Sonatas, piano, D. 960, B♭ major. Ray McIntyre, piano. undated.
      Brahms, Johannes, Intermezzi, piano, op. 117. Nr. 2. Ray McIntyre, piano. undated.
      Bach, Johann Sebastian, Partitas, harpsichord, BWV 830, E minor, Selections. Ray McIntyre, piano. undated.
    - Bach, J.S.: English suite no. 6. Ray McIntyre, harpsichord. Jack Bemis, oboe accompaniment. (Box 18)
      Bach, Johann Sebastian, Englische Suiten. Nr. 6. Ray McIntyre, harpsichord. Jack Bemis, oboe accompaniment. undated.
      McIntyre, Ray; Bemis, Jack
    - Telemann: Sonata; Schumann: 3 Romances for oboe and piano; Piston: piano and oboe sonata. Jack Bemis and Ray McIntyre, performers. (Box 18)
      Telemann: Sonata. Jack Bemis, oboe. Ray McIntyre, harpsichord. undated.
      Schumann, Robert, Romances, oboe, piano, op. 94. Jack Bemis, oboe. Ray McIntyre, piano. undated.
      Piston, Walter, Suites, oboe, piano. Jack Bemis, oboe. Ray McIntyre, piano. undated.
  - 10" reels
    - Bloch. String Quartet #3, Musart String Quartet, KFAC; Nielsen. Clarinet Concerto, 1953-12-27; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
      Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959. String quartet music; Nielsen, Carl, 1865-1931. Concertos, clarinet, orchestra, op. 57.
    - classical, numbered 91-93, 1952-1972; 3 audiotape reel(s) (Box 14)
      91. Organ KUSC 7-7-52, Robert Ellis of Fort Worth KPPC 7-9-52, Krenek Organ Sonata, Prokofiev String Quartet No.2, Ernest Kantiz Sonata Breve, Griffes The White Peacock Stokowski, NY Philharmonic
      92. Paul Muller Sinfonia No.12 For Flute and Strings, Op.53 Edmund de Stantz, Zurich Chamber Orchestra, Andre Jaunet, flute soloist / Weinrich plays Bach from Westminster LAB tape over KCBH 1-8-56
      93. Mozart Concerto #21 K.467 Szell, Casadesus / Ishii, Sogu II Ozawa Philidelphia 1972 (plus encore and interview)
    - Philip Corner Interview – Working Tape, 1989-12-27; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
      Corner, Philip
    - Peter Maxwell Davies interviewed by Martin Perlich, 1988-01-28; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
      Davies, Peter Maxwell, 1934-
    - Margaret Fabrizio at 1750 Arch, Holograms 1-3, 1976-10-29; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
      Fabrizio, Margaret
    - Flashback In History LP-66100 (E-19380) Henri IV, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
    - Global Village Reel 1, 1984-11-18; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
    - Captain J. Lovell, Original (Apollo 13 astronaut), 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
      Lovell, Jim
    - The Moveable Garden Narration Master, Sunset Films, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
    - Queen Elizabeth Coronation Ceremonies on WCBS #2, with S.F.Chronicle newspaper clipping from 1953-06-01, 1953-06-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
    - RCA Red Seal Showcase programs, 1983-04-13 & 1985-01-08, 1983-1985; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
    - Adrienne Rich Interview 1&2, 1990-04-13; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
      Rich, Adrienne Cecile
    - Rigoletto program with intermissions, 1980-01-19; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
      Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto.
    - Santana At His Worst, VT’s Compact Disc Show, 1986-10-25; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
    - Wagner, Furtwangler, or “Blank 1 ½ Voice Only”, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
    - WQXR Unicorn 8:30 September Chamber, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 4)
    - Joel Vandroogenbroeck - Digitalis Mystis In A Grand Piano With Birds. Stereo Master, 1985; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
      Joel Vandroogenbroeck (of 1970s Swiss progressive rock band Brainticket) was a Djerassi resident artist in 1985. The piece was written (and recorded?) at the Djerassi Foundation near Woodside, California.
  - videocassettes
    - VHS tapes, mostly opera, from various donors, 37 videocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Baller/Lobham Metropolitan Opera VHS tapes, 16 videocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Marriage of Figaro, Orpheus (all labeled “copy”), 6 videocassette(s) (Box 14)
      Marriage of Figaro. Bohm, Vienna Philharmonic (2 tapes); Marriage of Figaro. Levine, Met (2 tapes); Orpheus. Zurich Opera; Orpheus. Stravinsky, Bernstein, Thomas
    - Richard Crooks, 1971-12-02; 1 videocassette(s) Beta (Box 15)
  - unmarked and unidentified tapes
    - [unidentified], 4 audiotape reel(s) (Box 6)
    - Broben Tape, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 1)
    - "Roberta O’Neill (or Kapfenberg?)" – minimally notated, but two say “Les Claypool,” one dated 12-30-61 (two years before the Primus bassist was born), 1961-12-30; 6 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
    - [unidentified], 10 audiotape reel(s) (six 7” reels, four 5” reels) (Box 7)
    - unidentified live performance of orchestral music, early to mid-20th century, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12)
    - Unidentified tapes (possible Moran gift?), 39 audiotape reel(s) (Box 13)
      RCA Red Seal brand tapes, all opera and classical music, numbered 77-115 (works included are numbered 1708-2502).
  - audiocassettes
    - R.W. Goen, MD. Glyconutrients, What You Need To Know, 2003; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Janet Winters Conversation with Anne Loftis, 1983-12-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Rev. Don McArt. Two Science of Mind Lectures Delivered At The Science of Mind Church of Religious Science, Whittier, California. Keeping Cool 4/23/78; Mind Your Own Business 4/30/78, 1978-04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Sammy Kaye Orchestra air checks and live performances, 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
    - Martucci. Piano concerto, Defelle, Toscanni, NBC Symphony Orchestra; Rorem. Songs, D'Angelo, Gramm, Bressler, Rorem; Jongen. Suite en Deux Parties, folders (Box 16)
    - John Santos. Africa II, 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
      Track listings
      Side A: 1 - Elegua Ago 2 - Iya 3 - Toguey 4 - Health 5 - Zaire 6 - Modupue
      Side B 1 - Caridad 2 - Arere 3 - La La 4 - Machete
      Santos, John
    - Dianna Krall. Jazzset 980214, 1998-02-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
      Krall, Diana
    - James Barbagallo. Piano. Bach-Siloti Transcriptions, 1996-03-19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
      Works performed
      Side 1: Toccata and Fugue in D minor, BWV 565 Andante, from Violin Sonata No. 2, BWV 1003 Organ Prelude in G minor, BWV 535 Air, from Suite for String Orchestra No. 3, BWV 1068 Siciliano, from Sonata for Flute and Clavier, BWV 1031
      Side 2: Prelude No. 5, from Wilhelm Friedemann Bach Book, BWV 855 Chaconne, from Violin Sonata No. 3, BWV 1004
      Siloti, Alexander, 1863-1945; Barbagallo, James; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
    - Desolation Jazz Ensemble, Professor Plum's Jazz Band, Pismo Beach 1983, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
      Professor Plum's Jazz Band; Desolation Jazz Ensemble
    - Professor Plum's Jazz Band, High Sierra Jazz Band with Cal Abbott on clarinet, British Connection, Sticks/Strings/Hot Air, Pismo Beach 1983, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 16)
      Abbott, Cal; Sticks, Strings & Hot Air; Professor Plum's Jazz Band; High Sierra Jazz Band; British Connection